Now that we have a few useful words and phrases for telling stories let's tell a story we're gonna talk
现在我们有了一些有用的单词和短语来讲故事，让我们讲一个我们要讲的故事
about.
关于。
I'm going to talk about my memory of computers throughout my life.
我将谈论我一生中对计算机的记忆。
OK I'm going to talk about not only the functionality of the computers but I'm also going to talk about
好的，我不仅要谈论计算机的功能，还要谈论
some of my memories connected with them and hopefully when you hear my story you'll think oh it's a
我的一些记忆与他们有关，希望当你听到我的故事时，你会认为哦，这是一个
really interesting story and it might remind you of some things from when you were younger maybe maybe
非常有趣的故事，它可能会让你想起年轻时的一些事情
not.
不是。
Maybe we have different different experiences.
也许我们有不同的经历。
There are two very important tips that you need to keep in mind before I do tell this story about the
在我讲述这个故事之前，您需要记住两个非常重要的提示
progress of computers in my life through my own experience.
通过我自己的经验，计算机在我生活中的进步。
Number one and it seems very simple to say this but do not forget the past tense.
第一，这句话似乎很简单，但不要忘记过去时。
One of the most common problems for non-native English speakers English learners is that they forget
对于非英语为母语的英语学习者来说，最常见的问题之一是他们忘记了
the past tense when they should actually use it.
他们应该实际使用它的过去时。
This is a huge one.
这是一个巨大的。
It seems so basic and maybe you think it doesn't matter it's so small.
它看起来很基本，也许你认为它太小没关系。
It matters because when you're not careful about this you sound like you're clearly saying to other
这很重要，因为当您对此不小心时，您听起来像是在清楚地对其他人说
people I'm not a native English speaker.
我不是以英语为母语的人。
I'm not very fluent in English.
我的英语不是很流利。
It's so basic.
它是如此基本。
And yet often very hard because there are so many times to remember to do it.
但往往非常困难，因为有很多次要记住去做。
So it's got to become a deep habit.
所以它必须成为一个深刻的习惯。
Now how can you build that deep habit to remember to use the past tense when you know you should.
现在，当您知道应该使用过去时，您如何才能养成记住使用过去时的深刻习惯。
Well one of the problems that many people have is that they forget because they're speaking too fast.
许多人的问题之一是他们忘记了，因为他们说得太快了。
So what you can do is slow down when you learn the piano.
所以你能做的就是在学钢琴的时候放慢速度。
Do you start playing the piano.
你开始弹钢琴了。
Not at a limited level.
不在有限的水平。
No you start playing very slowly.
不，你开始玩得很慢。
Dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun right.
咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚咚。
Very slow Then you master it and increase your speed.
很慢然后你掌握它并提高你的速度。
Slow down.
减速。
Listen to what you're saying.
听听你在说什么。
Did you just say.
你刚才说吗。
And then I go to the store.
然后我去商店。
Did I just say and then I go to the store.
我刚才说，然后我去商店。
Oh I did.
哦，我做到了。
You need to say and then I went to the store or as I was going to the store.
你需要说然后我去商店或者我要去商店。
The point is you need to be able to hear what you just said what is coming out of your mouth.
关键是你需要能够听到你刚才说的话是从你嘴里说出来的。
Because that is the first step to being able to catch mistakes.
因为这是能够发现错误的第一步。
And the reason I always ask you to record after each lesson is that you can begin to listen to those
我总是要求你在每节课后录音的原因是你可以开始听那些
and hear where you're making mistakes and self correct.
并听到你在哪里犯错误并自我纠正。
The next step is to be able to hear them as you're speaking.
下一步是在你说话的时候能够听到他们的声音。
And if you speak slowly you can do that and then you're able to actually self correct maybe before it
如果你说得慢一点，你就可以做到，然后你就可以真正自我纠正，也许在它之前
even comes out of your mouth.
甚至从你嘴里说出来。
And then that sounds natural and that then will become a habit.
然后这听起来很自然，然后就会成为一种习惯。
And once it becomes a habit then you won't need to think about it anymore.
一旦它成为一种习惯，你就不需要再考虑它了。
I don't think about grammar when I speak English.
当我说英语时，我不会考虑语法。
I don't think about the past tense when I speak English.
当我说英语时，我不会考虑过去时。
It just comes out of my mouth.
它只是从我嘴里说出来。
It's such a deep habit.
这是一个很深的习惯。
So I want you to keep this in mind when you're telling your story that you don't need to do it quickly.
因此，当您讲述您的故事时，我希望您牢记这一点，您不需要快速完成。
There's no pressure to speak quickly.
快速说话没有压力。
OK.
好的。
That's the first thing.
这是第一件事。
The second thing.
第二件事。
The second tip you need to keep in mind is that no story is interesting if it's all details so make
您需要记住的第二个提示是，如果故事都是细节，那么任何故事都不有趣，所以
sure you connect emotion and memory to it.
确定你连接对它的情感和记忆。
What was your life like at that time.
那时你的生活是怎样的。
What other things were going on.
发生了什么其他事情。
How did you feel about that thing.
你对那件事感觉如何。
It's very important to connect those things to the details because if you don't then it's just a description
将这些事情与细节联系起来非常重要，因为如果你不这样做，那么它只是一个描述
of a thing which is very boring.
一件很无聊的事情。
People like to hear about how you felt at the time where people write where humans so keep those two
人们喜欢听你在人们写作时的感受，所以保留这两个
things in mind.
心中的事情。
Let's actually look at my story.
让我们实际看看我的故事。